You cannot contain what you are.
Glass is a thriller, drama, science fiction film directed by M. Night Shyamalan.
In a series of escalating encounters, former security guard David Dunn uses his supernatural
abilities to track Kevin Wendell Crumb, a disturbed man who has twenty-four personalities.
Meanwhile, the shadowy presence of Elijah Price emerges as an
orchestrator who holds secrets critical to both men.
Patricia / Dennis / Hedwig / The Beast / Barry / Heinrich / Jade / Ian / Mary Reynolds / Norma / Jalin / Kat / B.T. /
Kevin Wendell Crumb / Mr. Pritchard / Felida / Luke / Goddard / Samuel / Polly, played by James McAvoy.
David Dunn / The Overseer, played by Bruce Willis.
Elijah Price / Mr. Glass, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Dr. Ellie Staple, played by Sarah Paulson.
Casey Cooke, played by Anya Taylor-Joy.
Joseph Dunn, played by Spencer Treat Clark.
Glass is a 2019 American superhero thriller film written and directed by M.
Night Shyamalan.
It is a crossover and sequel to Shyamalan's previous films Unbreakable (2000) and Split
(2016) and the third and final installment in the Unbreakable trilogy.
Bruce Willis, Samuel L.
Jackson, Spencer Treat Clark, and Charlayne Woodard reprise their Unbreakable roles, while James McAvoy and Anya Taylor-Joy
return as their Split characters, with Sarah Paulson, Adam David Thompson, and Luke Kirby joining the cast.
The film sees David Dunn / the Overseer as he and Kevin Wendell Crumb / the Horde are
captured and placed in a psychiatric facility with Elijah Price / Mr.
Glass, where they contemplate the authenticity of their superhuman powers.
After the Walt Disney Studios' Touchstone Pictures opted not to finance a sequel to Unbreakable, Shyamalan set
out to write Split using a character he had written for Unbreakable but pulled from its script.
He decided to create a trilogy of works, using the ending of
Split to merge Glass with the Unbreakable narrative.
To secure the rights to use Willis' and Jackson's Unbreakable characters, Shyamalan
promised to include Disney in the film along with Universal Pictures.
Split was a financial and critical success, and by April 2017 Shyamalan
announced that he started the production process for Glass.
Glass had its world premiere in select Alamo Drafthouse Cinema theaters on January 12, 2019,
and was released in the United States on January 18 by Universal Pictures.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who found the film "disappointing" and "underwhelming" due to the story,
particularly the third act, but praised the performances of the cast; many deemed it the weakest in the trilogy.
The film was a financial success, grossing $247 million
worldwide against a $20 million production budget.
The film explores themes of philadelphia, pennsylvania,
superhero, villain, sequel, psychiatric hospital.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.